<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>

	<FantasyBiotech_LetterLabelConstructsFeral>Construct(s) gone feral</FantasyBiotech_LetterLabelConstructsFeral>
	<FantasyBiotech_LetterConstructsFeral>Some constructs(s) which were wandering without an overseer have linked with ancient planet-wide mech control signals. They have joined {0} and become hostile, and appear to be trying to fight their way off the map.\n\nFeral constructs cannot be resurrected at a gestator when killed.\n\nThese constructs are involved:\n\n{1}</FantasyBiotech_LetterConstructsFeral>
	<LetterLabelConstructlinkInstalled>Artificer implant installed</LetterLabelConstructlinkInstalled>
	<LetterConstructlinkInstalled>{PAWN_labelShort} has installed an artificer implant! {PAWN_pronoun} is now a artificer and can create and control constructs.\n\nResearch basic construct tech to get started.\n\n(*SectionTitle)Creating constructs:(/SectionTitle) Your artificer can create constructs at a production building called a gestator.\n\n(*SectionTitle)About bandwidth:(/SectionTitle) Artificers can control as many constructs as their total bandwidth allows. Select {PAWN_labelShort} and look at {PAWN_possessive} 'Bandwidth' readout to see how much bandwidth {PAWN_pronoun} is currently using and how much {PAWN_pronoun} has available. Bandwidth can be increased with certain apparel and by building band node buildings.\n\n(*SectionTitle)About control groups:(/SectionTitle) Artificers control constructs in groups. Each control group can be set to one of these modes:\n\n- Work\n- Escort\n- Recharge\n- Dormant self-charge\n\nTo learn more about what each mode does, select the work mode icon on one of {PAWN_labelShort}'s control groups and hover over the different work orders. The maximum number of control groups can be increased with apparel and implants.\n\n(*SectionTitle)About threat calling:(/SectionTitle) Artificers can signal ancient leader constructs to attack in order to obtain rare items from them. You must do this to improve your artificer past certain limits, but beware the danger.</LetterConstructlinkInstalled>

	<Fantasy_AlertGenebankUnfueled>Gene bank needs fuel</Fantasy_AlertGenebankUnfueled>
	<Fantasy_AlertGenebankUnfueledDesc>A gene bank is unfueled, so the genepacks inside it are slowly deteriorating. Refuel the gene bank to prevent the genepacks from deteriorating.\n\nOnce the gene bank is fueled, it will slowly reverse the deterioration of the genepacks inside it.</Fantasy_AlertGenebankUnfueledDesc>
	
	<FantasyBiotech_SteamNetExcess>Excess: {0} SPU ({1} SPUd Stored)</FantasyBiotech_SteamNetExcess>
	<FantasyBiotech_PipeSystem_NotConnected>Not enough steam in network.</FantasyBiotech_PipeSystem_NotConnected>
	<FantasyBiotech_SteamCharger_CurrentlyCharging>Currently charging {0}</FantasyBiotech_SteamCharger_CurrentlyCharging>
	
	<FantasyBiotech_Valve>Switches steam flow on/off.</FantasyBiotech_Valve>
	<FantasyBiotech_ValveDesc>Switches steam flow on/off. A pawn will come open/close the valve.</FantasyBiotech_ValveDesc>

</LanguageData>